<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ELEC1200 - A System View of Communications: from Signals to Packets on Spring 2021</title>
    <link>http://ryderdaniel.github.io/ELEC1200/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ELEC1200 - A System View of Communications: from Signals to Packets on Spring 2021</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 18:00:13 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ryderdaniel.github.io/ELEC1200/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture4</title>
      <link>http://ryderdaniel.github.io/ELEC1200/Lecture4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 18:00:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryderdaniel.github.io/ELEC1200/Lecture4/</guid>
      <description>Linear Time Invariant Systems Systems  For this class, a system is something that takes a waveform $x(n)$ and produces an output waveform $y(n)$ e.g. a channel.  Linear Systems  A linear system is a system that satisfies the following two properties:  Homogeneity:
$$x(n) \to |\text{ system }| \to y(n) \implies c \cdot x(n) \to |\text{ system }| \to c \cdot y(n)$$  If you scale the input by $c$ times, the output is also scaled by $c$ times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture3</title>
      <link>http://ryderdaniel.github.io/ELEC1200/Lecture3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 13:17:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryderdaniel.github.io/ELEC1200/Lecture3/</guid>
      <description>Representing Bit Waveforms Equivalent Representations of Waveforms  Verbal: The encoding of the bit sequence $1010001$ at 4 samples per bit. Graph:
 List, Table or Vector of Values:
$n = [0, 1, 2, 3, &amp;hellip;]$
$x(n) = [1, 1, 1, 0, &amp;hellip;]$ Sum of Unit Step Functions:
$x(n) = u(n) - u(n-4) + u(n-8) + &amp;hellip; + u(n + m)$  Uses for Different Representations  The four representations are equivalent in that if we know one, we can obtain any of the others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture2</title>
      <link>http://ryderdaniel.github.io/ELEC1200/Lecture2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 10:55:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ryderdaniel.github.io/ELEC1200/Lecture2/</guid>
      <description>Recap of Lecture 1 Representing Bit Sequences as Waveforms  A bit sequence can be encoded by changing the value of a physical variable over time Each bit is encoded by holding the state constant over a length of time known as the bit time. The shorter the bit time, the faster we can transmit information (bits).  Encoding information with Bits Bits  A bit is the basic unit of information used in modern computers and communication systems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>